Fangfang Xiao | Software FullStack Developer

226-978-0590 | fxiao.mecheng@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/fangfang-xiao | github.com/f2xiao | https://f2xiao.me/site

PROFILE

During my 4 year school in the Olympiad math special class, I cultivated a strong foundation for problem-solving and developed a genuine enjoyment for mathematical challenges. Today, I find that same passion and fulfillment in coding. My academic and professional background in engineering has also prepared me as a good problem solver and fast learner. I am ready to take on challenges and dive deep into the programming world.

SKILLS

Frontend: HTML, CSS, Sass, JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Vue

Backend: Node.js, ExpressJS, MySQL, MongoDB

PROJECTS

Lead Developer | NextWatch

MAY 2024, BRAINSTATION CAPSTONE

- Deployed and launched a full stack website with React for frontend and Node Js as backend
- Designed the UI and developed it TypeScript React for the frontend
- Integrated the backend with Express and MongoDB to facilitate user administration and data storage

Lead Developer | Instock

April 2024, BRAINSTATION Group Project

- Led a Agile team of 4 people to deliver an inventory management system within less than a week
- Reviewed teammates' code and offered support to overcome any blockers
- Managed the project by diligently updating the Jira board and promptly rectifying mislabeled tickets to ensure timely delivery

EDUCATION

BrainStation | Diploma, Software Engineering

FEB 2024 - MAY 2024, TORONTO, ON

University of Waterloo | Bachelors in Applied Science, Mechanical Engineering Co-op

Sep 2012 - AUG 2017, WATERLOO, ON

EXPERIENCE

Technical Forging Associate | Musashi Auto Parts

APR 2019 - MAR 2020, ARTHUR, ON

- Increased production efficiencies by Implementing a visual detection system that reduced defects by 10%
- Engineered the model of a conveyor system that automated the production line by saving 10% of time
- Communicated and sourced the suppliers that meet product specs and saved a cost of 10k

Project Engineering Coop | ABC Group Inc

MAY 2015- Sept 2015, ETOBICOKE, ON

- Led and directed various internal testings of new model launch with 100% passed
- Summarized testing results and reported to customers with a result of ahead of project timeline
- Submitted the pre-production samples with necessary certificates to customers with 100% passed